daysofourlives.com 2013-05-22

# Privacy Policy | Legal | Sony Pictures

* ##### NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

Pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, residents of the State of California have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed certain categories of personal information during the preceding year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes and the categories of personal information the company shares. Alternatively, the law provides that a company that has a privacy policy that provides consumers choice (opt-out or opt-in) regarding sharing personal information with third parties for their marketing purposes may instead provide information on how to exercise that choice. SPE qualifies for the alternative option; it has a comprehensive privacy policy that sets forth that SPE only shares personal information with third parties for direct marketing purposes if you specifically opt-in to such sharing at the time you provide personal information or at the time you choose to participate in a feature on the Sites. If you do not opt-in at that time, SPE does not share your information with that identified third party for marketing purposes. 

If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for marketing purposes and your ability to exercise opt-in choice, please send your request to the following email address: [SonyPrivacy@spe.sony.com](mailto:SonyPrivacy@spe.sony.com) and put the statement "Your California Privacy Rights" in the subject field of your e-mail. You must include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address. 

For more information about SPE's privacy practices, including when your information may be shared with third parties for purposes other than the marketing use by third parties, please review our full Privacy Policy. 

* ##### INFORMATION WE COLLECT ON OUR SITES

#### Information You Provide To Us

The Sites may ask you to provide information that could reasonably be used to contact you or to identify you personally (such as first and last name, e-mail address, telephone number, mobile phone number, or home address (" **Personal Information** "). For example, SPE may collect Personal Information when you register to receive newsletters, create user accounts, send questions or comments to us, or otherwise communicate or interact with us. The Sites may also ask you to provide other information about yourself, such as demographic information (gender, zip code, age, etc.) or certain information about your preferences and interests. If we combine demographic or other information we collect about you with Personal Information about you, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information. Please note that information submitted to the Sites via a "contact us" or other similar function may not receive a response. We will not use the information provided to contact you for marketing purposes unrelated to your request unless you agree otherwise.

##### Information We Collect Automatically As You Access and Use the Sites

Whenever you visit or interact with the Sites or SPE content, SPE, as well as any third-party advertisers, content providers and/or service providers, may use a variety of technologies that automatically or passively collect information about how the Sites are accessed and used (" **Usage Information** "). Usage Information may include, in part, browser type, operating system, the page served, the time, and the preceding page views. Usage Information is generally non-identifying, but if SPE associates it with you as a specific and identifiable person, SPE treats it as Personal Information.

SPE also automatically collects your IP address or other unique identifier (" **Device Identifier** ") for the computer, mobile device, technology or other device (collectively, " **Device** ") you use to access the Sites. A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device when you access a web site or its servers, and our computers identify your Device by its Device Identifier. Some mobile service providers may also provide us or our third-party service providers with information regarding the physical location of the Device used to access the Sites.

The technologies used on the Sites to collect Usage Information, including Device Identifiers, include: 

**_Cookies._** A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to visit the Sites. A Flash cookie is a data file placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-into or downloaded by you to your Device. Cookies and Flash Cookies may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, remembering you and your preferences and tracking your visits to our web pages. If you choose to disable cookies or Flash cookies on your Device, some features of the Sites may not function properly. 

**_Web Beacons._** Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons, (also known as "1x1 GIFs" or "clear GIFs") may be included in our Sites and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Sites, to monitor how users navigate the Sites, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to determine whether content sent was actually viewed. 

**_Embedded Scripts._** An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Sites, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Sites, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter. 

* ##### HOW WE USE INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH OUR SITES

SPE may use information collected through our Sites, including Personal Information, in order to: (1) allow you to participate in features we offer on the Sites; (2) process your registration, including, at times, verifying that the e-mail address you provide is active and valid; (3) provide you with information that you have requested or agreed to receive; (4) tailor content, advertisements, and offers we serve you; (5) improve the Sites and for internal business purposes; (6) contact you with regard to your use of the Sites, your account, and, in our discretion, changes to any SPE policy; and (7) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your Personal Information or otherwise with your consent.

If you use the Sites to send a friend an invitation to participate in the Sites or send other SPE- related communications, the information you provide (typically, names and e-mail addresses) is used on a one-time basis to facilitate the communication on your behalf, and is not used for any other marketing purposes unless we obtain consent from that person.

* ##### GENERAL AUDIENCE WEB SITES

The Sites are general audience web sites and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children younger than 13 years of age (" **Child** " or " **Children** "). However, SPE knows that certain Sites, such as those promoting a G-rated movie, may attract Children. On those Sites, SPE may request and collect e-mail address or other online contact information, which may include the online contact information of a Child, for one-time use of that information. For example, SPE may collect email address to allow visitors to receive a fun automated reply from a motion picture's character. After the online contact information is used once in connection with the specific purpose for which it was collected, we delete the online contact information from our records and do not use it to re-contact the visitor. Additionally, if we are notified that a Child has submitted Personal Information to us through any of our Sites other than in connection with one time use, we will delete that Child's Personal Information.

* ##### 

SPE does not share your Personal Information with third parties for their marketing purposes unless you opt-in to such sharing at the time you provide your Personal Information or at the time you choose to participate in a feature on the Sites. If you do not opt-in at that time, SPE does not share your information with that identified third party for marketing purposes. We may share non-Personal Information, such as aggregate user statistics, demographic information and Usage Information with third parties, and third parties, including third party advertisers, content providers, and analytics providers, may collect such information when you visit the Sites. We may also share your information as disclosed at the time you provide your information, as set forth in this Privacy Policy and in the following circumstances: 

**Third Parties Providing Services On Our Behalf.** We may from time to time employ third parties to perform functions on our behalf; examples include hosting or operating our Sites, executing IVR programs, sending e-mail and mobile message communications, and data analysis. We may share Personal Information with third parties in order for them to provide content or complete a requested transaction or otherwise perform services for SPE.

**When You Agree To Have Your Personal Information Shared.** While on our Sites, you may have the opportunity to opt-in to receive information and/or marketing offers from someone else or to otherwise consent to the sharing of your information with a third party. If you agree to have your Personal Information shared, your Personal Information will be disclosed to the third party and the Personal Information you disclose will be subject to the privacy policy and business practices of that third party. You also may specifically request, sometimes through your use of an interactive feature, a widget or an application, that we share information about you with a third party and we will typically do so under those circumstances. 

**Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions.** The Sites may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (each, a " **Promotion** ") that may require registration. If you choose to enter a Promotion, your Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties in connection with the administration of such Promotion, such as in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law, such as on a winners list. By entering a Promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor and/or other parties to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing materials. 

**Business Transfers.** We may share your Personal Information with other entities affiliated with us for internal reasons, primarily for business and operational purposes. SPE or any of its assets, including the Sites, may be sold, or other transactions may occur in which your Personal Information is one of the key business assets for the transaction. In such a case, your Personal Information may be one of the business assets we transfer. Hence, SPE reserves the right to disclose and transfer user information, including Personal Information in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of certain of SPE's stock and/or assets, or other corporate change including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

**Legal Protections and Law Enforcement.** SPE may transfer and disclose information, including your Personal Information, Usage Information and Device Identifier, (including IP address), to third parties to comply with a legal obligation; when we believe in good faith that the law requires it; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; to verify or enforce our [Terms of Use](http://www.sonypictures.com/corp/tos.html) or other applicable policies; to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property, safety, or security of third parties, visitors to our Sites or the public. We may also use Device Identifiers to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, Internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies, in our discretion. Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.

* ##### INFORMATION YOU DISCLOSE PUBLICLY ON OUR SITES

Our Sites may offer message boards, chat rooms, alternative reality games, multi-player games and other public areas (collectively, " **Community Forums** ") where you can engage in social networking, interact with others, as well as have the opportunity to submit photographs, writings, music, video, audio recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including Personal Information (collectively, " **User Submissions** "). To participate in certain Community Forums, you may be asked to select a username, screen name or member name and password. Please do not use your real name or the real name of another person when selecting a username (or screen name or member name). 

**_Note that anything you post to a Community Forum is public_** \-- others will have access to your User Submissions and may use it or share it with third parties. Information you choose to post or make available in the Community Forums may be viewed, collected and used by others. If you choose to voluntarily disclose User Submissions, the protections of this Privacy Policy will not cover such disclosure of information. Think carefully before you post and use caution before disclosing any Personal Information.

Also, functionality on the Sites may permit interactions between the Sites and a third party web site or service, such as enabling you to "like" a product on our Site or "share" content to other web sites or services. If you choose to "like" or "share" content on the Site or to otherwise post information from or via the Site to a third party's web site, service, feature or application, that information will become public and the third party may have access to information about you and your use of our Site.

User Submissions may be published online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed). We may also publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information with your User Submissions, and SPE may use the content, or any portion of the content, for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. For full terms and conditions regarding User Submissions you submit to the Sites, please review our [Terms of Use. ](http://www.sonypictures.com/corp/tos.html)

* ##### INFORMATION WE RECEIVE FROM THIRD PARTIES 

SPE may receive information about you from third parties. For example, if you are on another web site and you opt-in to receive information from SPE, that web site will forward to us your e-mail address and other information about you so that we may contact you as requested. You may also choose to participate in a third party application or feature on our Sites (such as logging in through Facebook Connect or otherwise linking the Sites with another web site or interactive service) or on a third party web site or service (such as one of our Facebook applications or a similar application or feature on a third party web site or service) through which you allow us to collect (or the third party to share) information about you, including Personal Information. When you choose to participate, you may be opting to link your activity on our Sites with that third party web site or service, which may then collect information about your visits to our Sites and may publish that activity as you request to your "profile" or similar feature with that third party (such as if you choose to share content you find on one of our Sites with your "connections" on the third party's web site or service). The information we collect is subject to this Privacy Policy. However, the information collected and stored by the third party remains subject to the third party's privacy practices, including whether the third party continues to share information with us or with other third parties, the types of information shared, and your choices with regard to what is visible to others on that third party's web site or service. The third party may allow you to remove the application or feature, in which case we will no longer collect information about you through the application or feature, but we may retain the information previously collected. In addition, we may receive information about you if other users of a third party web site or service give us access to their profiles and you are one of their "connections" or information about you is otherwise accessible through your "connections'" web page, profile page, or similar page on a social networking or other third party web site or interactive service.

We may also supplement the information we collect about you through the Sites with outside records from third parties in order to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our content to you and to offer you opportunities to purchase products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. We may combine the information we receive from these third parties with information we collect through the Sites. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to any Personal Information received, unless we have disclosed otherwise.

* ##### AD SERVING AND TRAFFIC MEASUREMENT SERVICES WE MAY USE; HOW TO "OPT OUT" OF RECEIVING ADVERTISING RELEVANT TO YOU

SPE licenses technology to serve advertisements on its own sites and within its videos and other content as that content is served across the Internet. In addition, SPE may use third party network advertisers to serve advertisements and third party analytics service providers to evaluate and provide us with information about the use of the Sites and viewing of our content. We do not share Personal Information with these third parties, but ad network providers, the advertisers, the sponsors, and/or analytics service providers may set and access their own **_cookies_** , **_web beacons_** and **_embedded scripts_** on your Device and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, including Usage Information. 

With regard to advertisements, we and our network advertisers may target advertisements for products and services in which you might be interested based on your visits to both the Sites and other web sites. **_Cookies_** and **_web beacons_** , including those set by third party network advertisers, may be used to, among other things, target advertisements, prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times, or to conduct research regarding the usefulness of certain advertisements to you. We may share Usage Information about visitors to the Sites with third party advertising companies for the same purposes. We may use a variety of companies to serve advertisements. You may wish to visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>, which provides information regarding the "opt-out" procedures of certain third party ad servers we may use. In addition, we work with a company called LiveRail, which offers a separate consumer opt-out, which you can access by clicking on the link below: <http://ad3.liverail.com/privacy/?optout>.

* ##### UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION AND OPTING OUT FROM EMAIL, SMS AND MMS COMMUNICATIONS

SPE may provide web pages or other mechanisms through which you can correct or update some of the Personal Information you have provided to us, including, without limitation, through registration with the Sites. You may opt out of receiving e-mail newsletters by following the opt-out instructions provided to you in those e-mails. If you sign up to receive SMS or MMS messages that may be offered on the Sites, you may unsubscribe from any SMS or MMS messages received by replying "STOP". Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of the Sites and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt-out from marketing communications. In accordance with our routine record keeping, we may delete certain records that contain Personal Information you have submitted through the Sites. We are under no obligation to store such Personal Information indefinitely and disclaim any liability arising out of, or related to, the destruction of such Personal Information. In addition, you should be aware that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases without some residual data because of backups and other reasons.

* ##### SECURITY

We incorporate commercially reasonable safeguards to help protect and secure your Personal Information. However, no electronic data transmission or storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use the Sites and provide us with your information at your own risk. 

* ##### THIRD PARTY CONTENT, LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES AND SERVICES, AND SPE CONTENT FOUND ON OTHER WEB SITES

Certain content on the Sites may be hosted and served by third parties, which may include third party widgets (such as those that allow you to "like" or "share" content with third party web sites and interactive services, or third party "get tickets and showtimes" widgets). In addition, when you are on the Sites you may be directed to other web sites or services that are operated and controlled by third parties. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use our logo(s) as part of a co-branding agreement. In addition, SPE Site widgets or other SPE content may be included on web pages, web sites and/or services that are not associated with SPE. We have no control over these third parties. These third parties may send their own cookies to your Device, they may independently collect data or solicit Personal Information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. SPE is not responsible for the privacy practices or business practices of any third party web site.

* ##### CONSENT TO TRANSFER 

The Sites are operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using the Sites, or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen.

* ##### NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES AND YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY; PRIVACY QUESTIONS

SPE reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy at any time, without prior notice to you, and any changes will become effective immediately upon posting. However, SPE will use your Personal Information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless you consent to the new or revised policy. If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at [SonyPrivacy@spe.sony.com](mailto:SonyPrivacy@spe.sony.com). 

_Effective Date_ : This Privacy Policy was updated on January 18, 2012 and is effective as of that date.
